HOANGYEN CAO

Seal Beach, CA | (805) 405–4869 | yenth602@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/hoangyentcao https://ghhyc.github.io

DATA ANALYST PROFESSIONAL

SUMMARY

Solution-driven professional with experience in programming analysis, particularly in healthcare. Skills in Excel, VBA, and Python for machine learning, statistical analysis, and programming. SQL (including ORMs) for programmable usage of database, and Tableau for data visualization. My teammates recognize me for project management, customer service, problem solving skills, and collaboration across diverse groups.

Tools: SQL | Excel | VBA | Python | Pandas | Matplotlib | API | Flask | Jupyter Notebook | Visual Studio Code | Tableau

Application: SQLite | PostgreSQL | SQL | Mongo DB | AWS S3& RDS | GitHub

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Ventura County Medical Center

SQL REPORT ANALYST (CONTRACT FOR LUMINOUS)

Ventura, CA 2015—2016

Develop, maintained clinical custom reports using Discern Visual Developer and CCL/SQL. Utilized CCL/SQL to analyze and validate data. Extract data from relational databases using SQL.

Pacific Hospital of Long Beach

System Analyst

Long Beach, CA 2012 – 2013

Developed and maintained clinical customer reports and created ad-hoc reporting tools using Discern Visual Developer, Power Insight, and CCL/SQL (CERNER/LINUX). Gathered user requirements, identified, and resolved problems. Support testing and implementation activities.

• Co-build tested and successfully implemented the Family Health Clinic project.

Aramark Uniform Services

Burbank, CA

Programmer Analyst

2008 - 2012

Health Net Inc.

Woodland Hills, CA

Programmer / Analyst

2001 - 2008

CERTIFICATIONS AND PROJECTS

UC Irvine

Data Analytics Bootcamp Certificate

Example project: Heart Disease Analysis https://github.com/ghhyc/project-4

Extract Transform Load (ETL)

https://heart-disease-predictor-p4.herokuapp.com

Using Heroku to deploy the app to the web. Machine modeling and data analysis to create an input page. Build the prediction page and

application route to obtain the prediction page.

Tools: HTML, Python, Jupyter Notebook, Pandas, AWS S3.

Example project: US and Electric Vehicle Analysis

Extract Transform Load (ETL) | https://github.com/ghhyc/electric-vehicle-charging

https://us-map-and-electric-vehicle.herokuapp.com

Using Heroku to deploy the app to the web. Extracted CSV files, Cleaned and imported files to PostgreSQL. Used Leaflet, D3 for display maps. Used any chart for display graph of State Level Emission Change.

Tools: HTML, Python, Jupyter Notebook, Pandas, Leaflet, and D3.

.

EDUCATION

California State University of Los Angeles

Bachelor of Science: Business Administration - Information System